# Felix Akoh

# Oracle Database Administrator - Bank of America

Charlotte, NC

felixakoh7\_2u5@indeedemail.com - 202-468-6535

#### **ORACLE DBA POSITION**

Hold over 7years of IT experience with 5years of extensive concentration and proficiency in ,Oracle 10g and 11g ,database design, administration and systems analysis geared at optimizing RDBMS functionality and productivity in production and non-production environments. I am also knowledgeable with Oracle 12C and great team player with a fast learning curve. I can work independently, perfectly and effectively under stressful conditions where speed and accuracy are necessary for business objectives to be met. I do not only have sound verbal and written skills but also mentor less experienced DBAs and write SOP's. My attention to detail and ability to maximize system resources can be beneficial in the following areas;

- Capacity Planning
- Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC)
- High Availability Implementation
- Database Upgrade and Refresh projects
- Database Security Enhancements
- · Backup and Recovery Strategy
- On call 24\*7 and offshore Support
- Optimal Database Performance
- Proactive Maintenance
- Incident Management
- Disaster Recovery Planning and Testing
- Internal and External Communication
- Oracle Golden Gate
- Oracle Exadata
- Oracle E-Business Suite

Oracle Database Administrator - Bank of America. North Carolina

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Oracle Database Administrator**

Bank of America - 2015-12 - Present

Created and maintained various databases for Production, Development and Testing using Oracle 9i, 10g, 11g.

Active member of the on-call team to support Clients of different Applications relating to our team 24/7, to keep the High critical systems running

Responsible for Data Guard setup with Primary and Standby Databases and scheduled.

Responsible for Oracle 10g RAC EE installation and configuration.

Responsible for setup ASM for Configuration of RAC.

Involved in configuring and supporting streams replication on oracle 10g.

Participate in storage capacity measurement and planning.

Managing database security, creating and assigning appropriate roles and privileges to users depending on the user activities.

Refreshed/cloned databases using RMAN utility.

Implementing Datapump, conventional export/import utility of Oracle 11g, 10g for re-organizing Databases/Schemas/Tables to improve the performance.

Used import/export utilities for cloning/migration of small sized databases and Datapump import/export to move data between 9i and 10g/11g environments.

Installed ASM environment and migrated databases from NON-ASM to ASM.

Monitored different databases and application servers using Oracle Enterprise Manager (OEM) 10g Grid Control.

Performed Database upgrade from Oracle 10g (10.2.0.5) to Oracle 11g (11.2.0.3)

Monitoring Cold, Hot and RMAN backup scripts of the databases supporting different applications.

Creation, configuration and setting up of RMAN catalog databases and registering target databases with the catalog.

Schedule jobs in crontab including RMAN backup and other memory maintenance, security jobs.

# **Oracle Database Administrator**

State Street Bank and Trust Co - Boston, MA - 2013-06 - 2015-12

Performed monthly and annual performance report for trend analysis and capacity planning

Participated in analysis and designing of Oracle Exadata Server for infrastructure and related projects. Assisted in integration of Exadata applications into current IT actionable events and solutions.

- Primary technical resources in SQL tuning in Exadata Production and Performance Testing environments by using statistics, hints, SQL tuning set etc.
- Integration of Exadata monitoring into our existing IT monitoring framework. Provide and implement performance and tuning recommendations of all components in the Exadata machines.
- Applying upgrade patch, maintenance and interim (opatch) patches on all the databases.
- Refreshing Dev and Test instances with data from Production on a regular basis.
- Developed PL/SQL packages, DML, DDL, Oracle tables, Stored Procedures, functions, cursors, triggers and UNIX shell scripts.
- Thorough knowledge in setting up infrastructure for databases in huge datacenters.
- Installed Oracle 11g on Linux platform using ASM.
- RMAN point in time recovery and Instance recovery done on 11g.
- Developed compliance reports and performed auditing at higher levels.
- Scheduling repetitive activities like gathering schema statistics, exports, table space usage report using crontab
- Experience in writing UNIX/SHELL scripts for providing the reports.
- Installed and configured Oracle 11g database on a test server using Oracle standard procedures and OFA, for performance testing and future 10g production implementation.
- Applied PSU Patches as a part of maintenance activity.
- Extensively used Datapump, conventional export/import utilities for loading data to & from databases, logical backups and migration of databases.
- Monitoring and optimizing the performance of the database/application using OEM along with homespun scripts.
- Capacity planning: Allocate system storage and plan future storage requirements.
- Worked on SQL tuning using SQL Tuning Advisor, SQL Access Advisor, SQL Profiler and SQL Optimizer.
- Monitoring rollback segment and temporary table space use.
- Performing housekeeping tasks like checking log and trace files.

- Responsible for setting and managing USER MANAGEMENT, SPACE MANAGEMENT Granting required privileges to users.
- Assist in SQL tuning and providing consultation such as creating Materialized views, adding indices, dropping unnecessary indices, using hints wherever possible, amongst others.
- Worked on both VMS and UNIX environments.
- Troubleshooting of various database performances by proper diagnosis at all levels like SQL, PL/SQL, database design, database tables, indexes, Instance, memory, operating system and java calls.
- Knowledge in Oracle Data warehouse DBA skills relating to administration and management of VLDB environments, Oracle OLTP

Created ETL test data for all ETL mapping rules to test the functionality of the Informatica Mapping

• Tested the ETL Informatica mappings and other ETL Processes (Data Warehouse Testing Environment: Oracle 12C, Oracle 11g oracle 10g, VMS, Sun Solaris, Windows Server 2003, Red Hat Linux, TOAD, RMAN, SQL server, OEM .Microsoft SQL ,Oracle E-bussiness suite ,Oracle financials

# **Oracle Production Support Database Administrator**

General dynamics company - Warrenton, VA - 2013-06 - 2013-06

Successfully installed and configured Oracle 11g Oracle 10g databases on AIX platforms

- . 24 X 7 Production & Development database support and administration Oracle Exadata
- Monitored different databases and application servers using Oracle Enterprise Manager (OEM) 10g Grid Control.
- Loading data from flat files to database using SQL\*Loader, External Tables.
- Extensively used AWR, ADDM and explain plan for periodic performance tuning.
- Implementing Datapump, conventional export/import utility of Oracle 11g, 10g for re-organizing Databases/ Schemas/Tables to improve the performance.
- Used import/export utilities for cloning/migration of small sized databases and Datapump import/export to move data between 10g and 10g/11g environments.
- Implemented proactive monitoring using Tuning Pack, Diagnostics Pack, and STATSPACK, SQL Trace & TKPROF, EXPLAIN PLAN.
- Database monitoring/maintenance, replication process and performance tuning are done using OEM (Oracle Enterprise Manager).
- Implemented Flashback technology of the Oracle 11g, 10g for a faster recovery of the databases and database objects.
- Performed full & incremental backup (cumulative and differential) using RMAN and implemented recovery strategies.
- Refreshed/cloned databases using RMAN utility.
- Performed Database upgrade from Oracle 10g (9.2.0.7) to Oracle 10g and to Oracle 11g on RAC database.
- Successful in applying RDBMS patches, security patches for improving the security and functionality of the databases.
- Achieved optimized performance for the databases by rebuilding indexes, on tables and indexes.
- · Automated the processes like moving files, managing alert log, efficient backup by developing UNIX scripts.
- Involved in the installation, configuration and extended support to Oracle 11g, 10g two Node RAC (Real Application Cluster) with ASM file system on AIX platform.
- Involved in converting a single instance database to Oracle 11g, 10g RAC databases.
- Installed ASM environment and migrated databases from NON-ASM to ASM.
- Used TOAD for database management.
- Made optimal use of Oracle Support in resolving the SRs.
- 24 X 7 Production & Development database support and administration Oracle Exadata

Environment: Oracle 11g oracle 10g IBM AIX V6.1, RHEL 5.2, RAC, ASM, RMAN, AWR, ADDM, SQL\* Plus, SQL\*Loader, OEM, TOAD 10.0. Microsoft SQL, NOSQL

#### Oracle Junior DBA / SQL Server DBA

AT&T - Middletown, NJ - 2012-01 - 2012-06

Installed and configured ORACLE 10g on HP-UX and Windows NT.

- Performed Upgrades of databases from Oracle 8i to Oracle 10g.
- Planned and implemented physical backup (both hot and cold) & recovery procedures for the database using RMAN utility of Oracle 10g.
- Creating the users and assigning them the required privileges.
- Provided 24x7 on-call support as needed.
- Implemented coalescing when required by monitoring the database for fragmentation.
- Performing table space management, monitoring data files additions, extent growth, normalization, indexing as a part of day-to-day activities.
- Done resetting of storage parameters by series of exports and imports of tables, used conventional as well as direct path loads to upload the data into the server using SQL loader.
- Prepare the documents of the process and knowledge transferring about the project to the new team members.
- Created, maintained and troubleshoot PL/SQL objects, shell scripts and utilities.
- Implemented proactive monitoring using STATSPACK, SQL TRACE & TKPROF, EXPLAIN PLAN.
- Separated the indexes, data, rollback segments and redo log files on separate disks to minimize contention, Monitored the buffer cache hit ratio and the dictionary cache miss ratio. The DB\_BLOCK\_BUFFERS and SHARED\_POOL\_SIZE were increased, resulting in tremendous improvement in performance.
- Installed, Configured and Administered SQL Server 2012/2008R2/2008 Servers in Production, QA, Pre-Prod and Dev environments.
- Responsible for overall database environment and maintain operational uptime of 99.9%.
- Installed and managed multiple 3 node failover cluster set up in active/active clustered environment as a High Availability mechanism.
- Performance tuning, capacity planning, trend analysis, and server sizing for very large databases.
- Daily support, troubleshooting, monitoring, optimization and tuning of server and SQL server environments across entire system.
- Extensively worked on MS SQL security and Active Directory Security administrator
- Implemented Transactional Replication for different applications and managed replication and database modifications for replicated objects
- Monitoring the servers using third party software and backups using SQL Litespeed.
- Ticketing systems like Resolve for Change Request, Sales Force, BMC Remedy etc.,
- Created logins and Roles with appropriate permissions for temporary and permanent access requests

Environment: Oracle 11g oracle 10g IBM AIX V6.1, RHEL 5.2, RAC, ASM, RMAN, AWR, ADDM, SQL\* Plus, SQL\*Loader, OEM, TOAD 10.0. NOSQL

### **EDUCATION**

# B.s in Management of Information Technology in Management of Information Technology

University of Yaoundé 2009-08

#### **SKILLS**

Database, databases, OEM, Oracle, Oracle 10g

# ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

#### SKILLS SUMMARY

- Experienced in Performance Tuning using EXPLAIN PLAN, TKPROF, and STATSPACK.
- Expert in implementing High Availability solutions with Oracle 11g RAC, Oracle Data Guard and replication using Streams.
- Planned and implemented high availability solutions such as Real Application Cluster (RAC) in Oracle 11gR2 Grid and 10g on ASM and OCSF2 file systems.
- Highly experienced in Oracle 11g, 10g Automatic Storage Management (ASM) required to fulfill the storage needs.
- High ability to analyze and understand the AWR reports and can fine tune the databases for maximum performance.
- Extensively managed users, privileges, profiles, schemas using Oracle Enterprise Manager (OEM).
- Configured Oracle Enterprise Manager (OEM) Grid Control (in Oracle 11g, 10g) for the purpose of monitoring multiple databases and application servers.
- Highly experienced in using Oracle 10g features Flash-Back Recovery and Recycle Bin.
- Experience with Oracle 11g/10g in Installation, Administration, Monitoring, Database Backup and Recovery.
- Proficient with Database Cloning, Migration, and Patching of Oracle Databases.
- Upgrade/Migration of oracle databases from 10g to 11g and 10gRAC to 11gRAC.
- Worked on Set up, configuration and maintained Oracle Data Guard/Active Data Guard to control Primary and Secondary databases and also to ensure disaster recovery using various data protection modes.
- Expert in RMAN backups including full, incremental and cumulative.
- Excellent knowledge in Flashback Recovery, Hot/Cold Backup and Cloning/Refresh of databases using RMAN. Experience in applying patches/ patch sets to the databases.
- Extensively worked on Import/Export and Data Pump Import/Export tools.
- Knowledge in configuring ASM (Automatic Storage Management)
- UNIX Systems Administration Database and application integration efforts. Heavy UNIX shell scripting, CRON jobs.
- Proficient in complete, incomplete recovery of the database, Point in Time Recovery (PITR), and Tablespace Point in Time Recovery (TSPITR) using RMAN utility.
- Expertise in implementing partitioning methodologies (Range partitioning, List partitioning, Hash partitioning, Composite partitioning) on tables and indexes for high performance.
- Knowledge of Database Recovery Techniques and implementation of those recovery techniques to ensure business continuity.
- Expertise in maintaining Database Security using auditing.

#### TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

Operating Systems HP-UX 10.x, 11.x. Sun Solaris 2.5, 2.6, 8, 9, 10. AIX 5.1, 5.2, 5.3, 6.1 RHEL 2.1, 3.x, 4.x, 5.x.Linux Enterprise Server 9, 10. Windows

RDBMS Oracle 10g, 11g Microsoft SQL Oracle 12C NOSQL

Languages SQL, PL/SQL, UNIX Shell Scripting, PERL.

Tools TKPROF, EXPLAIN PLAN, STATSPACK, AWR, and ADDM.Toad, Putty, NX client, Winscp. Database Utilities

SQL\*Plus, Oracle Enterprise Manager, Real Application Cluster, ASM, Transportable Tablespaces, SQL\*Loader, RMAN, DataPump, Export, Import